<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tips_Tricks</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techtracker5.github.io/category/tips_tricks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/</link>
	<description>&#60; Technology Simplified &#62;</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 09:29:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/cropped-Screenshot_20240625-153951-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Tips_Tricks</title>
	<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Best Battery Tips &#038; Tricks For Android &#8211; 2020</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2020/03/27/best-battery-tips-tricks-for-android-2020/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kernel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lithium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips_Tricks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2020/03/27/best-battery-tips-tricks-for-android-2020/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Battery of smartphones getting bigger day by day and even getting chargers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/best-battery-tips-tricks-for-android-2020.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/best-battery-tips-tricks-for-android-2020.webp" width="320" height="180" alt="best-battery-tips-tricks-for-android-2020"></a></p>
<p>Battery of smartphones getting bigger day by day and even getting chargers that can charge phone in less than 30min so what about old smartphones and you are heavy user then these battery tips definitely useful.</p>
<p>&#8211; Battery Saving Tips / Tricks &#8211;</p>
<p>• Put the apps in hibernating mode so that the apps will not use external resources that do effect your battery getting drained you can easily do that installing greenify app •</p>
<p>• if you are using battery in normal mode then enable batter saver or super battery saver in samsung •</p>
<p>• if you are using any unauthorized app or game that may be using uneccessary permissions check carefully and remove them uninstall if possible •</p>
<p>• don&#8217;t charge the battery to 100% charge it to 95&#038; or above 80% to get good battery time • </p>
<p>• if you are not using the device turn off the internet and put the device in airplane mode so that you can save battery in needy times • </p>
<p>• Use Dark wallpaper in amoled displays so you can save a little battery • </p>
<p>• You can try LSpeed magisk module or app &#8211; root required that can save your battery and extend battery time • </p>
<p>• You can even turn on data saver as it will limit the data recover that can reduce load so that the little battery time can be extented • </p>
<p>&#8211; This is our small tips and tricks for battery that can be useful &#8211; </p>
<p>• </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips &#038; Tricks For Youtube</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2020/01/09/tips-tricks-for-youtube/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 09:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Improve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips_Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2020/01/09/tips-tricks-for-youtube/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi, do you likely to start a youtube channel or to improvise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/tips-tricks-for-youtube.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/tips-tricks-for-youtube.webp" width="400" alt="tips-tricks-for-youtube"></a></strong></p>
<p>Hi, do you likely to start a youtube channel or to improvise then wait read our tips &#038; trips and make a wonderful youtube channels in very less time.</p>
<p>It is useful to share your content and knowledge using YouTube throught out the world, but there are alot of channel and get views and subscribers there is alot of things that you need to keep in mind and improvise your channel accrording to it.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see the tips that will improve your channel.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #1</strong></p>
<p><strong>Channel Name</strong> : First things that you have take care of is to use a channel name that suits you channel and make good structure and sound.</p>
<p>Likely using techytimes instead technology times.</p>
<p>would give you a better output and less length and good sound.</p>
<p>Take sometime and create a good username that youtube only accept limited change requests up</p>
<p>to 3 for 90days.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #2</strong></p>
<p><strong>Description :</strong> Yes, Give a good</p>
<p>description that apt your work of channel and provide brief explanation that definately make people to see more of your content and do provide contact information for further support or questions and provide bussniess</p>
<p>email looks professional.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #3</strong></p>
<p><strong>Logo :</strong> Creating a good logo gives you a seperate identity and brand take some time and build a good logo that apt your channels and a perfect size cover picture to look good and clean.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #4</strong></p>
<p><strong>Custom Link :</strong> After creating youtube channel you will have default channel url go to youtube setting in desktop and change the url to short and cool.</p>
<p>Custom url have many benefits as it&#8217;s give short and exact name of your channel.</p>
<p>YouTube Needs atleast 100 subscriber base to get a custom url.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #5</strong></p>
<p><strong>Videos :</strong> Give good time in producing quality and informative videos and take some sufficient time in editing and publish.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #6 </strong></p>
<p><strong>Intro :</strong> Make a good intro for your channel for videos as it will become professional vibe in your channel there are numerous softwares available and if you want to create online there are cool websies to do but most websites have watermark for free video if you want no watermark you can put but looks really cool and professional.</p>
<p>You can make free intro&#8217;s to on your own either in kinemaster or free intro making software or apps.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #7</strong></p>
<p><strong>Outro</strong> &#8211; As important as intro, make an good outro that end of your video with show casing your social media</p>
<p>usernames that gives good recognition and reach to your users.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #8</strong></p>
<p>If your are creating teaching videos or online tutorials : moovly.com provides good features you can use whichever you like.</p>
<p>Whatever category you are working on use a good software that have potential to edit more.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #9</strong></p>
<p><strong>Camera :</strong> if you are making direct interactive class or teaching or gaming or any kind of physical appearence videos choose a good camera if you are</p>
<p>are a vlogger use a gimbal if it doesn&#8217;t fit use stabilization software or use a camera that have high stability.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #10</strong></p>
<p>Create video starting intresting &#038; ending interesting as make your videos interacting with your audience does boost your audience feel more channel centric.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #11</strong></p>
<p>Create a website in the name of your channel and add in your description and video, do active in It does give good reputation and fan base.</p>
<p>These are some tips that give a good visibilty and pro look to you channel.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #12</strong></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t ever use sub4sub or any other yotube detets spam subscribe and it can block your channel.</p>
<p>However, your content should be unique, interesting and quality for growth.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #14</strong></p>
<p>Create live streams for your videos so it can give audience to chat and do live streams to answer on questions or to interact with viewers.</p>
<p><strong>Tip #15 </strong></p>
<p>Keep consistency, yes upload atleast 3 videos in a week with good quality and content.</p>
<p>Finally, Quality over Quantity and Be Consistent.</p>
<p><strong>#Tricks</strong></p>
<p><strong>Trick #1</strong></p>
<p>Description : Give a good length of description of your videos and provide links for products that use.</p>
<p>Trick #</p>
<p>Watermark : Add watermark to your videos even though youtube algorithm can detect most copyright videos and you ability to strike.</p>
<p>If your content embedded or used somewhere you can get direct audience to your channel with watermark.</p>
<p><strong>Trick #3</strong></p>
<p>Use udemy.com or some tutorial website there are free and paid tutorial available to improve youtube channel use them.</p>
<p><strong>Trick #4</strong></p>
<p>Advertise : Yes, even after giving good content still your not getting attention or youtube not display then advertise with website and youtube channels or partner with fellow youtuber&#8217;s to increase subs and views.</p>
<p>These are some tricks that can be useful we will add more soon.</p>
<p>Keep Supporting : TechTracker.in</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Useful Tips &#038; Tricks For Seo</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2020/01/07/useful-tips-tricks-for-seo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sinium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips_Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Website]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2020/01/07/useful-tips-tricks-for-seo/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you are starting a website or you are completely new to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/useful-tips-tricks-for-seo.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/useful-tips-tricks-for-seo.webp" alt="useful-tips-tricks-for-seo" /></a></p>
<p>If you are starting a website or you are completely new to these website things, there are so many ways to build a complete and today it become to easy with the available resources we have and everybody can make a site and live up in min with free cme system from trusted global companies.</p>
<p>Even with the easyness the competition become really as daily lakhs of pages created daily as it&#8217;s become very hard if you wrote an article about something&#8217;s and its appear in google or any other search engine.</p>
<p>So to do better and there is a solution to have a place in google search with a good seo and mainly content should be unique and quality.</p>
<p><strong>Seo</strong> <strong>Tips &#8211;</strong></p>
<p><strong>&#8211; Domain Name</strong></p>
<p><strong>Yes,</strong> first and foremost is choose a good domain name that apt your work and good word search capability as it will decide your future website run-up choose website domain consciously give some time if necessary.</p>
<p><strong>&#8211; Content Management System</strong></p>
<p>There are free and paid content management systems either like blogger, wordpress, medium, squarespace, postach.io, pen.io and many more</p>
<p>and most website give you unlimted space if you use thier subdomain else charged as they have have some of them have own paid services as some do offer free like blogger.</p>
<p>If you don&#8217;t wanna paid service you can opt for free hosting sites to add your domain they are many available &gt;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.techtracker.in/byethost.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">byethost.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.techtracker.in/awardspace.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">awardspace.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.techtracker.in/freehosting.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">freehosting.com</a></p>
<p>Choose your own cms or hosting according to your need as they have both pros and cons based on the preference and need of features vary on all of them.</p>
<p>As if you are choosing hosting instead of cms then choose a paid hosting if your are working for long time or professional then choosing hosting gives more security and privacy with guarantee of support and no down time.</p>
<p><strong>• Design</strong></p>
<p>Give more time to design as it matters alot that needed to apt the work and give a good look does reach more audience, of your can make your own design give more time to design, if not choose a good theme or template that is seo friendly or make it seo friendly.</p>
<p>• <strong>Title</strong></p>
<p>Give a tile that match your content and reflect your work in simple words and it does help alot in future.</p>
<p><strong>• Description of Your Site</strong></p>
<p>Take time use some trendy and grammar checked as it will appear below your site that make people click give a good description within keyword limit.</p>
<p>• <strong>Meta Keywords</strong></p>
<p>Use trending words that going on for your page category and add them wisely as it will boost the audience reach.</p>
<p><strong>• Social Media</strong></p>
<p>Create accounts like facebook, Instagrams twitter so your posts can reach more people in this portal as it develops customer available, interaction and reach including that value.</p>
<p><strong>• Article &#8211; Title</strong></p>
<p>Good title makes people read your article, how, why use good title that ensure reach and viewship.</p>
<p>•<strong> Article</strong></p>
<p>Google doesn&#8217;t accept less length articles so give a good lenth and quality article and mainly quality over quantity keep this in mind.</p>
<p><strong>• Article Start And Ending</strong></p>
<p>Start with a travel going experience and end with a question mark or give a good supportive ending and don&#8217;t bore of with unnecessary stuff make interesting and subjective.</p>
<p><strong>• Search Description</strong></p>
<p>Google or any search engines take some from article to show up in index so if your are ablevto give a good line description you can do that for a better reach and viewership.</p>
<p><strong>• site map</strong></p>
<p>Create a site for yor site map to inform search engines about updates of yor sites you can easily create a site map.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/</a></p>
<p>Use the above website and save it and use whenever needed.</p>
<p>• <strong>Google Analytics </strong></p>
<p>If you wanna better about your site visitors and reach of countries and most used devices and time that uses stayed on your website and many plenty of features add your site</p>
<p><a href="http://www.techtracker.in/www.googleanalytics.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">www.googleanalytics.com</a></p>
<p>• <strong>Bing &#8211; Microsoft</strong></p>
<p>Add in bing and submit your site for using plenty of features and bing is giving 100$ advertising credit and have a look as it was second most global using search engine after google.</p>
<p>• <strong>Backlinks</strong></p>
<p>Add Backlinks if necessary as it gives google to search for a specific site can get your udjence as your listed the link that people are searching for.</p>
<p>• <strong>Tags or Lables</strong></p>
<p>Give Lables to your article as it gives designated keyboards to related articles</p>
<p>• <strong>Category</strong></p>
<p>Make category and add the article&#8217;s according to the category that it suits so it will maintain clean and easy of usage</p>
<p><strong>• Load</strong></p>
<p>•Google likes to rank website based on speed as the research that google released most users will leave page if it was more than 3seconds, even thought google says that most websites today atleast have 20seconds of load time.</p>
<p>•To decrease load time of your site you have to minimise scripts or content that reduce the request limit for a better speed.</p>
<p>•speed of the website based on several things like</p>
<p>internet speed, size of the website, resource etc.</p>
<p>• as earlier said do minimise scripts and other resources and reduce size and internet speed vary user to users so making a general speed.</p>
<p>&gt; To reduce size you have minimise HTML and CSS of your site as wordpress offers several plugins to do that you can install it and use.</p>
<p>But blogger doesn&#8217;t have option now to do that go to htmlcompressor.com edit your XML template copy your code paste it in the site choose blogger tick minify html and css ut8 encoding and compress and compress ultra then you&#8217;ll get compressed code copy it and paste it in your template.. done</p>
<p>&gt; Another way to reduce size is to optimise images to do that go to tinypng.com upload and get compressed img.</p>
<p>&#8211; <a href="http://www.techtracker.in/tinypng.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">tinypng.com</a></p>
<p>&#8211; <a href="http://www.techtracker.in/highcompress.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">highcompress.com</a></p>
<p>&#8211; <a href="http://www.techtracker.in/compressor.io" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">compressor.io</a></p>
<p>Some times that can compress imgs at different sizes with ability to choose compression rate.</p>
<p>You can even do compression with Adobe Photoshop and other compression softwares by reducing img quality.</p>
<p>In android you can use <strong>pixel lab.</strong></p>
<p>If you still not satisfied, there is an easy way install telegram and upload to saved messages and get your image compressed.</p>
<p>If you are uploading in article blogger resizing to bigger size than you many uploading img in blogger android as the app doesn&#8217;t have option to upload in google use website or use client blogger pro.</p>
<p><strong>• Submit Your Site </strong></p>
<p><strong>Yes,</strong> one of the first thing after completing offline stuff submit your site to search engines for free.</p>
<p>There are several websites.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.entireweb.com/free_submission/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">https://www.entireweb.com/free_submission/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.submitexpress.com/free-tools/free-website-submission/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">https://www.submitexpress.com/free-tools/free-website-submission/</a></p>
<p>After submitting your site will be crawl by search engines.</p>
<p>Use this below sites, that have to ability to inform that your site is updated,</p>
<p><a href="https://pingomatic.com/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">https://pingomatic.com/</a></p>
<p>After completing of submit your website.</p>
<p>• <strong>CDN</strong></p>
<p>Use cdns like cloudflare, keycdn etc as cloud flare optimize your site alot and do cover domain ownership giving security and free ssl.</p>
<p>• <strong>SSL</strong></p>
<p>Security matters, get a free ssl as it validate and ensure your site is geniune and spam and if your site is shopping and must needed for secure payments as more likely geniune sites ranks</p>
<p>Http to Https &gt; Red to Green : Stop And Go</p>
<p><strong>• Mobile Friendly</strong></p>
<p>Most of the users are from mobiles, the better the mobile it ranks the better the reach and usage take some time and work on it.</p>
<p><strong>Lastly content is more important even though this tips helps alot as new your content the better it will get audience.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tricks &gt;</strong></p>
<p>Yes, there are alot of tricks that can make your site better and check problem.</p>
<p>• <strong>Seo Checker</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.techtracker.in/Neilpatel.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Neilpatel.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.techtracker.in/Prepostseo.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Prepostseo.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.techtracker.in/Sinium.com" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Sinium.com</a></p>
<p>Give your site a test with this site and check issues or where the site lack and fix them.</p>
<p>This Sites have several features like pinging, security, Backlinks builder, rewrite articles and many more must try as most of them tricks are there in the sites.</p>
<p>Use sinium mobile app.</p>
<p><strong>&gt; Ranking Tools</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Alexa Rank Checker</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Moz Rank Checker</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Page Authority</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Seo Report Card</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; Research Tools</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Adsense Calculator</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Broken Links Finder</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Code to Text Ratio</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Dmoz Listing</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Google Cache</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Link Analyser</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Mobile Friendly Test</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Page Size Checker</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Serp Keyword Position</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Social Stats</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Source Code</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Spider Simulator</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Links Counter</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Redirect Checker</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; Performance Tools</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Gzip Compression</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Server Status</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Webpage Speed Test</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Image Optimized</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; On Page SEO </strong></p>
<p><strong>• Meta Tags Analyser</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Meta Tags Generator</strong></p>
<p><strong>• HTTP Headers</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Keywords Density</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Keyword Suggestions</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; Off Page SEO</strong></p>
<p><strong>• BackLinks Checker</strong></p>
<p><strong>• BackLinks Builder</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Seach Engine Pinger</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; Blog And News Seo</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Article Rewriter</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Word Counter</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Grammar Checker</strong></p>
<p><strong>• WordPress Ninja</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; Domain Tools</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Class C Checker</strong></p>
<p><strong>• DNS Records</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Domain Age</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Domain Authority</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Domain Availability</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Domain IP lookup</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Reverse IP lookup</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Hosting Provider lookup</strong></p>
<p><strong>• URL Encoder And Decoder</strong></p>
<p><strong>• W</strong><strong>hois</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; Security Tools</strong></p>
<p><strong>• AVG Website Scan</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Google Malware Scan</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Black List Lookup</strong></p>
<p><strong>• MD5 Generator</strong></p>
<p><strong>• URL Rewriting Tool</strong></p>
<p><strong>&gt; Other Tools</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Email Extractor</strong></p>
<p><strong>• My Browser Info</strong></p>
<p><strong>• My IP Address</strong></p>
<p><strong>• Website Worth Estimate</strong></p>
<p>This tools have specific importance used according to your need some website to have some tools some not but sinium have most tools available : sinium.com or app and</p>
<p><strong>Advertise</strong></p>
<p>Even though if you content have potential, do use some bucks to advertise as it will ensure more reach and growth</p>
<p>Finally, Check your Alexa and moz rank to get improve and updated timely.</p>
<p>Keep supporting : TechTracker.in</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 ways to improve browsing speed in smartphone</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2019/12/24/10-ways-to-improve-browsing-speed-in-smartphone/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[browser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Improve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips_Tricks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2019/12/24/10-ways-to-improve-browsing-speed-in-smartphone/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi, Welcome Everyone has atleast once experienced network issue and slow speed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/10-ways-to-improve-browsing-speed-in-smartphone.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" height="180" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/10-ways-to-improve-browsing-speed-in-smartphone.webp" width="320" alt="10-ways-to-improve-browsing-speed-in-smartphone"></a></p>
<p>Hi, Welcome</p>
<p>Everyone has atleast once experienced network issue and slow speed due to several reason either lack of towers in your area or you live in unreachable places even your network provider doesn&#8217;t give high speed data in your geo location there are numerous reasons that you may faced this network issues and slowspeed&#8230;</p>
<p>Keeping this In mind Facebook launched Facebook lite and google added page lite features it does improve the speed but is it enough ? </p>
<p>Well no. In this article you&#8217;ll know some useful tips and tricks that will help you to increase your internet and browsing speed.</p>
<p>Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p>First, Generally either you are running Android or iOS you&#8217;ll probably have setting option apps and now you have to go into that option and restrict unecessary apps from background usage these way the network and battery will improve both battery and network speed is inter-connected and do enable battery optimization.</p>
<p>Second, go to your playstore or appstore and search for network restrict for apps you&#8217;ll get some apps that have ability to restrict apps that either taking higher data and you can check any unusual or unecessary app and restrict internet according to your preferences.</p>
<p>Third, using lite versions apps rather than original apps, apps that was higher size and resource required will take higher usage if you have option choose a lite version app like fb lite, and messanger lite, twitter lite etc over original versions the lite versions are made to speed at less data or network so you won&#8217;t face much problem.</p>
<p>Fourth, Facebook as you may know or not Facebook apps has known for battery reducer, Facebook does consume alot of internal storage and keep on continuing in background it does take alot of internet at the same time so better to put it in optimization mode at the same time restrict background usage will suggest to use fb lite for things that needed mostly and use fb app for features that are not added yet in facebook app.</p>
<p>Fifth, updating your software time to time these thing can actually increase your internet speed as the fixes or improvements from your phone manufactures will fix bugs so this can possibly improve your internet speed.</p>
<p>Sixth, dns, adding a custom dns settings will do the better job then a system dns, there are some amazing free dns providers from reputed companies that not only improve the loading speed at the same time block your glitchy adds that open in new tabs unecessarly.</p>
<p>Here are some dns providers go to setting and add this url in dns option and save it.</p>
<p>dns.adguard.com</p>
<p>cloudflare : you can even install app for this in playstore.</p>
<p>Or, add these  &#8220;1dot1dot1dot1.cloudflare-dns.com&#8221; url in dns settings.</p>
<p>Seventh, using vpn over normal, vpn does not only provide security from getting hacked or keep you safe from internet attacks. And choosing a right high speed vpn service boost the internet speed. And if there&#8217;s is any unnecessary outflow internet from your device will be closed.</p>
<p>Eight, some times may your lack some settings that needed specifically for your device or your sim network provider contact to your network providers and ask for the settings and install them this could definitely improve the speed as setting may change sometimes </p>
<p>Nine, probably installing as many apps from unknown sources and remaining with it and giving unecessary permissions can possibly making internet slow try to uninstall apps which are unecessary.</p>
<p>Tenth, lastly of your are still facing network issues then only way to solve the problem is contacting your network provider and asking your problem and fix your issue if still doesn&#8217;t changed then reboot your device that could fix things up else changing sim to another network may help you.</p>
<p>Honarable mention &gt;</p>
<p>Some browsers like kiwi and puffin do offer cloud browsing optimizing result like upto 50% more speed than usual so check out them even at low internet speed works pretty fast and moreover puffin is personal favorite for us you can compare yourself and decide.</p>
<p>These are some useful tips and tricks that may solve your network and speed issues.</p>
<p>Keep Supporting. : TechTracker.in</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
