<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iOS</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techtracker5.github.io/category/ios/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/</link>
	<description>&#60; Technology Simplified &#62;</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 09:23:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/cropped-Screenshot_20240625-153951-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>iOS</title>
	<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to install iOS on Android, it&#8217;s absolutely possible now.</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2022/10/13/how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Android smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[install]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2022/10/13/how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[iPhone 1 released by popular personal computer maker Apple inc. founder Steve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" width="400" alt="how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now"></a></p>
<p>iPhone 1 released by popular personal computer maker Apple inc. founder Steve Jobs on January 9, 2007 is world&#8217;s first multi-touch technology smartphone which has closed source powerful hardware and advanced software at first it has no name but from iPhone 2 it is known as iOS which came to replace keypad mobile phones.</p>
<p>Apple inc. was able to sell iPhone in almost all of it&#8217;s stores across globe mainly in USA and they used to go out of stock in few minutes due to high demand from customers standing in big queue out of stores to get thier hands on iPhone 1 and it&#8217;s upcoming versions despite it&#8217;s quite costly that effected and dropped sells of keypad mobile phones which is why most companies to hold market and get track on business begin making plans to make smartphones like iPhone.</p>
<p>Even though, there are number of big mobile companies which have potential and capability to make top notch quality hardware smartphone but what they lack is operating system basically software like iOS at that time in November 2007 search engine giant Google unveiled Android and then later on released it as free and open source project on web known as AOSP.</p>
<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/1_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/1_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" width="400" alt="1_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now"></a></p>
<p>Google actually acquired Android in year 2005 from Andy Rubens but for whatever reasons it was not released until year 2008 when HTC a Taiwanese company launched world&#8217;s first Android powered smartphone named HTC Dream or G-1 after that many mobile companies who are unable to use iOS started developing and using Android to make and ship smartphones globally.</p>
<p>The advantage of Android is it&#8217;s not only allow anyone to build and use it on thier smartphones but also customize and do more optimizations or enhancements as per requirements like adding or removing options and features or changing GUI aka graphical user interface etc due to that we got amazing custom Android softwares.</p>
<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/2_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/2_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" width="400" alt="2_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now"></a></p>
<p>Android build out of AOSP without any external modifications or changes known as stock that can be seen on Google&#8217;s own smartphones like Nexus and Pixel but alot of people don&#8217;t like to use stock instead they prefer custom ones as they come with numerous cool additional features and options unavailable on stock Android version which are quite useful for sure.</p>
<p>Now, we have number of fantastic feature rich Android custom softwares to name few Xiaomi MIUI, Tecno&#8217;s HiOS, Meizu&#8217;s Flyme OS etc with alot of custom skins and themes which played one of the main role in driving Android towards success but still many people like iOS that in fact lack customization to level of Android yet preffered thanks to closed eco system.</p>
<p>iOS undoubtedly provide more security and privacy then Android as it&#8217;s closed source and restrict users from installing apps from third party sources and no custom launchers as well due to such limitations and expensive price of Apple Inc. iPhone alot of people in developing countries like India prefer to buy low cost Android powered smartphones.</p>
<p>It is possible that you may also own Android as it&#8217;s dominant mobile operating system with more then 70% world wide market share but in case you are not satisfied with it&#8217;s user interface instead wanted iOS for various reasons may be you like or got used to it as an existing user of iPhone then we have number of iOS launchers and custom roms.</p>
<p>Usually, majority of people who can&#8217;t afford iPhone want to get feel and essense of iOS on Android which is possible thanks to it&#8217;s open eco system where alot of talented developers over the years build and released many iOS themed launchers with widgets and custom roms can be installed on Android smartphones to get vibes of iPhone&#8217;s iOS very well.</p>
<p>iOS launchers available on Android has some cons like missing widgets and in-complete themes despite thier millions of downloads on Google Play an Android&#8217;s app market place which won&#8217;t provide full fledged experience of iOS that&#8217;s why iOS custom roms are as best choice.</p>
<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/3_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/3_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" width="400" alt="3_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now"></a></p>
<p>Thankfully, many skilled developers build custom roms using AOSP then themed it to look like iOS which is not easy task and require assistance from graphic designers which may be the primary reason most custom rom developers usually don&#8217;t like to make iOS themed custom roms instead build stock roms or port existing custom themed Android roms like Sailfish OS.</p>
<p>Now a days, custom rom developers due to no self interest or demand from people  not making iOS themed custom roms but back then few years back iOS themed custom roms are popular which is why most likely there will be atleast one iOS themed custom roms available on old Android smartphones especially on those that are one decade ago.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re lucky enough to have an old Android smartphone then you may try finding iOS themed custom rom build exclusively for your device on trusted platforms like XDA but there is another problem here most iOS themed custom roms are old so you won&#8217;t find new user interface and features available on new iOS versions available on latest iPhones.</p>
<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/4_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/4_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now.webp" width="400" alt="4_how-to-install-ios-on-android-its-absolutely-possible-now"></a></p>
<p>In case, you don&#8217;t care about either it&#8217;s old iOS version all you want is just get look of iOS on Android smartphones may be for nostalgia reasons then it&#8217;s fine for that first you have to do is first unlock your device bootloader then install custom recovery like CWM or TWRP etc after that install iOS themed custom rom specifically build for your device by following given instructions available available on XDA that will totally void device warranty.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, when you flash any custom recovery or rom incorrectly that was not build for your device then your smarphone will either hard or soft brick so be careful including that many old iOS custom roms not themed in operating system instead use iOS launchers like Espier launcher that may not liked by everyone but it&#8217;s fine.</p>
<p>In sense, custom roms are bit difficult to handle by newbies who don&#8217;t know anything about technology if you&#8217;re one of them and don&#8217;t want to risk your Android smartphone in any manner then it&#8217;s better to stay away from iOS or any other custom roms and use iOS launchers and widgets available on platforms like Google Play to be in safe and secure zone.</p>
<p>However, if you strongly insist to get new iOS software available for your device then you can develop it for yourself if you don&#8217;t know how to do that then you may have to ask help or hire custom rom developer and graphic together to create new iOS themed custom rom for your Android device which will indeed going to be fabulous.</p>
<p>GUI of iOS is intuitive that&#8217;s why many people like it but not everyone instead they like and wanted certain features of iOS on Android like for instance iOS dynamic island feature got immense popularity world wide which was ported as an app on Android that you can try right now likewise you will find many more available out there on world wide web of internet.</p>
<p>Finally, this is how you can get iOS software on Android using iOS launchers and custom roms, are you an existing user of any one of them then do say your experience and why either your like iOS launchers or custom roms and mention is your device have iOS custom rom in our comment section below, see ya 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nicegram &#8211; A Telegram client for iOS with awesome features !</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2020/12/31/nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Client]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2020/12/31/nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before, getting started in the eve of new year we are distributing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features.webp" alt="nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features" width="400" /></a></strong></p>
<p>Before, getting started in the eve of new year we are distributing premium promo codes of nicegram a single promo code for one individual worth 0.99$ which will give you premium features of nicegram for our channel followers &amp; blog readers.</p>
<p>To win these promo code do follow our telegram channel <a href="http://@techtracker_in/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@TechTracker_IN</a> and take screen shot of it and do message to our bot the first 10 members will get the promo code.</p>
<p>Twitter &#8211; <a href="http://t.me/TechTracker_IN" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@TechTracker_IN</a></p>
<p>Our bot &#8211; <a href="http://t.metech_tracker_bot/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@Tech_Tracker_bot</a></p>
<p><strong>Nicegram</strong> &#8211; a well known telegram client developed by Sergey Akentev for iOS this client provide extra features that don&#8217;t exist in official telegram.</p>
<p>Nicegram have amazing features that are not available in official telegram app and it is currently only available for iOS platfrom.</p>
<p>This telegram client made using official telegram API complying TOS so you will get perfect app for telegram usage who follow all ethical measures.</p>
<p><strong>Eventhough</strong>, the first version of nicegram was 5.4.1 yet 5.7 version released in app store infact nicegram is new it is just a year but got huge popularity in app store with <strong>4.1</strong> rating which is impressive.</p>
<p>It has to be mentioned nicegram is open source you can see the code in Github it does mean nicegram is safe and secure you can rely on the app as you can check the code anytime to check issues.</p>
<p>If you have any doubt regarding privacy of this app as per app store it doesn&#8217;t collect any kind of information still if you want to know detailed info check <a href="https://nicegram.app/privacy-policy" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">privacy policy</a> of nicegram.</p>
<p>It is interesting to see nicegram even have a in app purchase premium version while the official app itself doesn&#8217;t have and they struggling to monetize telegram, telegram should take nicegram as an inspiration 🙂</p>
<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/1_nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/1_nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features.webp" alt="1_nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features" width="400" /></a></p>
<p><strong>° The story behind nicegram °</strong></p>
<p>The founder and developer shared us story behind Nicegram for iOS.</p>
<p><strong>Tech Tracker</strong> : Sergey, can you share us your story behind Nicegram !</p>
<p><strong>Sergey Akentev</strong> : so, I&#8217;m a backend engineer with more than 5 years of experience, I&#8217;m a telegram enthusiast who fond of creating bots and related software.</p>
<p>Switching from android to iOS, I realized that telegram app for iOS is not very comfortable for me. I&#8217;ve been looking for chat folders, filters, unblocked content and improved translator.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been searching for customization client with same features for a long time, but there were only old unsupported versions.</p>
<p>I was not familiar with mobile coding but with all the knowledge and Google I&#8217;ve successfully build the swift app using github sources and pushed first beta version to the testFight.</p>
<p>App was named &#8220;Nicegram&#8221; because it&#8217;s a &#8221; Nice Telegram&#8221;. I want to show everyone that&#8217;s how nice the telegram app can be.</p>
<p>Nicegram got a lot of positive feedback from my first testers. the day I realized who if not me will create best iOS alter- native telegram client? there the long &amp; cool story of nicegram begins!</p>
<p><strong>Tech Tracker</strong> &#8211; Thank you ✌</p>
<p><strong>° App Info ✨</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/2_nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/2_nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features.webp" alt="2_nicegram-a-telegram-client-for-ios-with-awesome-features" width="400" /></a></strong></p>
<p><strong>° What&#8217;s new ✨</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Updated</strong>] <a href="https://nicegram.app/unblock" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Chats &amp; Messages unblock method</a></li>
<li>Forward As Copy (without Author)</li>
<li>Save to Cloud button for fast forwarding to your saved messages.</li>
<li>Fast user restrict from context menu</li>
<li>Support up to 10 accounts</li>
<li>Messages translator via GTranslate</li>
<li>[Premium] Quick Translate button</li>
<li>Ability to hide contacts tab &amp; tab names</li>
<li>Themed bottom folder list</li>
</ul>
<p>Other Features are not re-implemented yet 😩</p>
<p>Nicegram now supports 7.3 sources with Voice Chats in Groups, Announce Messages with Siri and more!This also includes some fixes for Premium on non-latest devices and improvements for translator.</p>
<p>For more details &#8211; <a href="https://nicegram.app/7.0/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p>Check version history &#8211; <a href="https://nicegram.app/changelog/" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p>Translate &#8211; <a href="https://nicegram.app/translate" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p><strong>° Nicegram key features °</strong></p>
<p>Nicegram returns you the joy of pure communication:</p>
<p>&#8211; Get more focus with Folders &amp; Tabs. Group chats by topic you want, or split them by type &#8211; channels, bots, private and more. Be productive on the messaging fields!</p>
<p>&#8211; Hide unused Tabs. Decide whether you need to hide or show Contacts and Calls tabs at the bottom of your app.</p>
<p>&#8211; Forward messages without author tag.</p>
<p>&#8211; Translate incoming messages or activate Premium to get quick translate shortcut button.</p>
<p>&#8211; Switch between ten accounts. Multiple accounts now mean more than three, that&#8217;s limited in a standard Telegram Messenger app.</p>
<p>&#8211; Instantly Save Messages to your Cloud with a single tap.</p>
<p>&#8211; Admin like a boss. Restrict users faster than a bullet. Long tap a message and proceed to an exception menu.</p>
<p>&#8211; Nicegram is not only NICE. It is SAFE to use. Don&#8217;t just take my word for it. Go and check yourself the source code at <a href="https://github.com/nicegram" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Github</a>.</p>
<p>&#8211; Unblock chats</p>
<p>&#8211; Ghost mode</p>
<p>&#8211; Premium Beta</p>
<p>• FAQ &#8211; <a href="https://nicegram.app/faq" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p>This are just some of the key features of nicegram for more detailed brief features explanation go to website &#8211; <a href="https://t.me/nicegramapp" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p>Donate &#8211; <a href="https://www.patreon.com/nicegram" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p>° <strong>Nicegram Official Support °</strong></p>
<p>• Official Channel: <a href="https://t.me/nicegramapp" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegramapp</a></p>
<p>• 🇬🇧 English chat: <a href="https://t.me/nicegramchat" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegramchat</a></p>
<p>• 🇬🇧 Developer Blog (insides &amp; beta): <a href="https://t.me/nicegramdev" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegramdev</a></p>
<p>• 🇷🇺 Русскоязычный чат: <a href="https://t.me/nicegram_ru" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegram_ru</a></p>
<p>• 🇨🇳 Nicegram 中文讨论组: <a href="https://t.me/nicegram_cn" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegram_cn</a></p>
<p>• 🇹🇼 Nicegram 臺灣討論群: <a href="https://t.me/nicegram_tw" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegram_tw</a></p>
<p>• 🇮🇹 Nicegram Italia: <a href="https://t.me/nicegram_it" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegram_it</a></p>
<p>• 🇹🇷 Nicegram Türkçe: <a href="https://t.me/nicegram_tr" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegram_tr</a></p>
<p>• 🇪🇸 Nicegram Español: <a href="https://t.me/nicegram_es" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegram_es</a></p>
<p>• 🇩🇪 Nicegram Deutsch: <a href="https://t.me/nicegram_de" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@nicegram_de</a></p>
<p>• 🇮🇷 Nicegram Persian Channel: <a href="http://t.me/nicegram_fa" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p>• 🇮🇷 Nicegram Persian Chat: <a href="https://t.me/joinchat/BZq6jw10HFkJ9Hxn7lzwqw" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
<p><strong>Moreover</strong>, nicegram provies amazing customer support for people around the world with many languages.</p>
<p>Contact <a href="https://t.me/Kylmakalle" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@Kylmakalle</a> if you want to be part of a tiny team (which includes only me 😁)</p>
<p><strong>Finally</strong>, The dedication that Sergey Akentev puts in this app just amazes me, this app definitely need to be praised for being up to date facing challenges and struggles to give android telegram user experience in iOS, are you a user of nicegram do convey your user experience in our comment section below, see ya 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Apple Struggling In India Market ?</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2020/03/02/why-apple-struggling-in-india-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budget]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2020/03/02/why-apple-struggling-in-india-market/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tech Tracker &#124; Apple Inc, the glorious days of apple until the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/why-apple-struggling-in-india-market.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/why-apple-struggling-in-india-market.webp" width="320" height="180" alt="why-apple-struggling-in-india-market"></a></strong></p>
<p>Tech <strong>Tracker</strong> | Apple Inc, the glorious days of apple until the Steve jobs being CEO of the company with a lot of enthusiasm, innovation and trend setting accomplishments.</p>
<p>Then the need of CEO required due to death of Steve jobs then Tim Cook Became CEO and continued apple being the popular first choice in countries like USA and some European countries.</p>
<p>Apple primary focus on quality in depth and innovation where today innovation lacks quality excels as usual but apple have huge fanism due to thier great achievements in time of Steve jobs.</p>
<p>Apple, smartphones mainly excells in camera, gaming, stability and security to the users giving a closed portal with in build benefits for a better secured device that making a major role in buying apple smartphones.</p>
<p>&#8211; Why Apple Struggling In India ?</p>
<p>&#8211; Less Options</p>
<p>&#8211; Less Features</p>
<p>&#8211; Over Hyped </p>
<p>&#8211; Availability</p>
<p>&#8211; Value</p>
<p>&#8211; Price </p>
<p>&#8211; Repair Charge&#8217;s</p>
<p>• Apple do have less options to choose unlike samsung or Nokia you won&#8217;t be having a entry device or budget device primarily made for Indian market.</p>
<p>Example : Apple launched iPhone xr which said to be entry level device in view of apple with 720p display not even HD display that the price is 70,000rs which the entry level price market in india is 7,000rs with specs of minimum 1080p display.</p>
<p>Eventhough, apple gives best in it specs on paper specs shows different effect on Indian consumer where lack of experiencing apple devices become problem for various reasons.</p>
<p>India is one of the largest populated country where the salary of a person ideal is 10k per month with this ideal salary getting a 720p display phone in 70k is not value for money.</p>
<p>Indian consumers give high priority to value for money as apple give vibrant look with the carefully curved adverts to over hype thier below average specs in Indian market which doesn&#8217;t work as Indian customer&#8217;s choose smartphone after a lot of research and usage.</p>
<p>Repair charges one of the main reason apple takes the price of half of the phone to repair or replace parts and to buy the accessories then it is also the same scenario while budget phones are getting fast charging apple taken years and to get far lesser voltage which really won&#8217;t workout in Indian markets.</p>
<p>Usability, india is android dominated smartphone country which android known for customization and free control to users while iPhone put firewall to features and usability.</p>
<p>To make India users to get used apple products, apple have to give products at lesser price, apple struggle with taxes and import charges making iPhone more costly than usual price.</p>
<p>No apple stores, apple does partner with Indian sim network which doesn&#8217;t really succeed well still there is not even one official store available in india and yet apple struggling, apple knows india is future development hub with young ratio so apple doesn&#8217;t want some other company to handle thier products so they doing research carefully to get open thier retail stores which gives a + point to thier gain in sells but until the price reduce their is very less possibility of reaching apple products to every Indian household.</p>
<p>The problem with apple in india</p>
<p>&#8211; Quality &#8211; √ | Specs &#8211; × | Camera &#8211; √ |</p>
<p>&#8211; Value &#8211; × | Repair Charges &#8211; × | Price &#8211; ×</p>
<p>This are some of the main reasons that apple struggling in india market the India mobile market have great potential once boomed it will chase for years for a brand like apple which have great reputation and value among Indians eveb though most people not interest and unable to afford for on paper no value product but apple need to promote thier quality at best they definitaley has to open retail stores for a better reach.</p>
<p>Finally, apple still maintains quality but innovation lacking which Steve jobs not even digest the fact that apple being ruined with no improvised timely and sticking to older golden structures set by Steve jobs, however lack of interest and effort in large hike making apple to struggle in india market unless apple think of releasing india centric devices its hard to cope up anywhere near future and Indian smart customers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Iphone Over Android ?</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2019/12/26/why-iphone-over-android/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 10:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2019/12/26/why-iphone-over-android/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple : iPhone iphone&#8217;s come long way since the launch of iphone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/why-iphone-over-android.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/why-iphone-over-android.webp" alt="why-iphone-over-android" width="400" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Apple : iPhone </strong></p>
<p>iphone&#8217;s come long way since the launch of iphone 2g it does revolutionized the entire mobile phones viewing and using ways to the public and made new advancements like never before than the competitor Android has it own lineup like nexus and pixels.</p>
<p>iphone&#8217;s being the most purchased devices in United States and Europe and considered as most security focused eco system and software.</p>
<p>In terms of hardware apple makes its best software and design even though the foxicon Chinese company fix things at right place the design of iphone done in California.</p>
<p>Now you will know why the iphone can be taken over Android on basis of pros&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TOE7L8vbhuk/XgohTuvpr0I/AAAAAAAAAYY/o81xy3lnGosEYfLIglLTfE7ZdpbJyPz9gCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/IMG_20191230_213851_636.jpg" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/1_why-iphone-over-android.webp" alt="1_why-iphone-over-android" width="320" height="179" /></a></p>
<p>iPhone provides you an ecosystem that make to stick to it in way that everything that can be connected to you with apple devices like Mac , i message, apple watches and its own cloud storage etc these will be useful if you are completely like the iphone and choosing iphones and apple products over any other.</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-e4LzEJdj9NQ/XgohmdKv8LI/AAAAAAAAAYg/_iU8C9f6XxIJCkpVsm8wwc81d0FY219KwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/IMG_20191230_214034_021.jpg" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/2_why-iphone-over-android.webp" alt="2_why-iphone-over-android" width="320" height="179" /></a></p>
<p>iPhone has its own software iOS , it does provide software updates and security focused with an closed source and it&#8217;s very hard to hack a iphone so it makes users be privacy free if you are the person who like privacy is the main priority considering iphone is a good choice.</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZUh8DanW1yY/Xgoh8LZcHfI/AAAAAAAAAYo/E8bgieakbLUjo1yJ9WwN0P4lee3JrTMawCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/IMG_20191230_214220_494.jpg" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/3_why-iphone-over-android.webp" alt="3_why-iphone-over-android" width="320" height="213" /></a></p>
<p>Display even taught the display numbers of iphone are not big but the quality will mesmiriser that a 720p screen of iphone can match a amoled display of samsung 1080p and apple uses its own retina display using thier mods to hd and it&#8217;s making a good release to the market and to experience the iphone retina display check out the comparison in youtube.</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-j2AlqpgetJM/XgoiO4vZTVI/AAAAAAAAAY0/GOFHf6ND0JwWro62PZQBH1t_uesDMcDkQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/IMG_20191230_214303_274.jpg" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/4_why-iphone-over-android.webp" alt="4_why-iphone-over-android" width="320" height="213" /></a></p>
<p>Camera iphone camera are top notch in either photography or video mode the stability and usage are more better than in android the detail and sharpness are more crisp, iphone can easily beat android in terms of actual image capturing.</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nTouwmNvJMA/XgoimfENRzI/AAAAAAAAAZA/iRpd9LTM4jUAJT8k8c8zDWF6yGeBP_aKwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/IMG_20191230_214502_071.jpg" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/5_why-iphone-over-android.webp" alt="5_why-iphone-over-android" width="320" height="240" /></a></p>
<p>Apps in appstore comparision to android playstore are less but interms of apple taking care of every app is good the apps whichever release in app store are completely checked carefully and released so you more likely not getting any virus or trojans at the same time apple app quality and ui experience really feel quality experience.</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fHUZKpGOCKk/Xgoi8F4kDKI/AAAAAAAAAZI/arb9lIqP31kHBlRlfz5DazdpXt2c2yPugCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/IMG_20191230_214600_644.jpg" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/6_why-iphone-over-android.webp" alt="6_why-iphone-over-android" width="320" height="213" /></a></p>
<p>Design, design of apple was one of the most influenced and inspired model for many companies mainly for Chinese companies the design feels rich and unique if we considered apple and pixels more likely the fans for apple will be more still its individual preference.</p>
<p>Updates Iphone give users software updates for years if you really wanted a phone that can drive for years then owning a iphone is better while android struggles in terms of it unless you own a pixel.</p>
<p>iPhone is pricy compared to android and owning a iphone is a stature symbol in india considered by some but iphone doesn&#8217;t lack anywhere in terms of quality and user experience.</p>
<p>If you going for iphone for above then definately iphone is better over android.</p>
<p>Keep supporting : TechTracker.in</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Truth Of Apple&#8217;s Qwerty Keyboard</title>
		<link>https://techtracker5.github.io/2019/12/13/the-truth-of-apples-qwerty-keyboard/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Evans]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keyboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techtracker.free.nf/2019/12/13/the-truth-of-apples-qwerty-keyboard/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple&#8217;s Qwerty Keyboard, Yes you heard it right. QwertyKeyboard that you in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/the-truth-of-apples-qwerty-keyboard.webp" data-wpel-link="internal"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://techtracker5.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/the-truth-of-apples-qwerty-keyboard.webp" width="320" height="180" alt="the-truth-of-apples-qwerty-keyboard"></a></p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s Qwerty Keyboard, Yes you heard it right.</p>
<p>QwertyKeyboard that you in your devices either it&#8217;s android and windows or another software that using that was patented by apple&#8217;s.</p>
<p>The story goes back in time when Steve jobs and apple engineering developing apple iOS phones.</p>
<p>Steve jobs being an inspiration of entrepreneurs and being an amazing entrepreneur himself, he got the nerve beat and mindset of the people, as there is a sad story behind the apple inc Steve jobs left the apple company as the other team members decided they taught Steve jobs ideas getting bad so it will effect majorly to the company in the race of Microsoft windows and apple&#8217;s I Mac.</p>
<p>When these unexpected problem in front of Steve jobs, however he accepted it and left the company with a minor share. So he could watch and join in the metting and know about the company, later he joined after apple was in losses after request of share holders.</p>
<p>You may think&#8230; Why I&#8217;m highlighting keyboard while there are many other inventions that was patented by apple like multitouch etc.</p>
<p>Now you&#8217;ll know, apple was started in a car garage and company started by selling Steve jobs own van with this friend who was inventor of  advanced keyboard that was later adapted by other companies and it still in use till now and continuing&#8230;</p>
<p>When apple was looking for an alternative for hardware qwerty keyboard that&#8217;s already being used by Nokia and Samsung etc.</p>
<p>The apple ecosystem is all in a touch screen interface, whatever that needed to do should have to be done in 3.5 inch screen ( which is big screen considered at the time ) so they are in dailema of finding an alternative and well adapting to apples iOS software, the development process has been started and ordered apples engineer to work on it.</p>
<p>The other software and hardware things are adding and modifying stage, apples engineers have be showing up and presenting their methods none of them really satisfied Steve jobs,</p>
<p>One fine day a engineer of applè came up with the qwerty keyboard and it amazed everyone including Steve jobs, it was fast, easy to use, sleek and well adapted to iOS ecosystem and its a big advancement for any multi touch device and forth coming devices.</p>
<p>Later qwerty keyboard have become a computer keyboard for everyone and it make forgot of computer keyboards another major reason being  public waiting in lines for days infront of smartphone and apple vendors.</p>
<p>After the buzzing slowed down, android adapted it in their eco system which later got features like voice, emojis and write and text emojis and some years after dark and lights mode skins etc. </p>
<p>This looks simple but the advancement it was done is marlavellous it changed human day life and everything you doing in internet must require a qwerty keyboard without that you have been using old style hardware buttons.</p>
<p>There is no doubt you won&#8217;t see any other alternative for qwerty keyboard in years for any software either its android or apple even kai is to use this as default the better things has not yet popped up or either it will can&#8217;t guaranteed, google was working on fuschia os for using four apps at a time, do we get some thing like qwerty can&#8217;t say until a complete fuschis os release.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s keep using qwerty keyboard until then&#8230; </p>
<p>Moreover a big thanks to the engineer from us.</p>
<p>Conclusion : old style bored new things needed for apple when need for keyboard for utilising multi touch search started development orders passed engineers worked day and night none of them impressed Steve jobs, a engineer all of a sudden presented it mindblowed everyone and later got adapted by every ecosystem, that made an revolution like never before never again you in 2019 using it and not finding an alternative for your phone software, you have only option its none other than qwerty keyboard.</p>
<p>Keep Supporting : TechTracker.in</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
